Cameron Leach

949.422.4800 | cameron.leach@gmail.com

Profile

Accomplished executive with over 15 years of professional software engineering experience and a proven track record of leading high-impact, smoothly executed projects. A people-first leader known for making teams better by establishing a collaborative culture focused on detailed and quality execution to deliver exceptional products and results.

Experience

Disney

Santa Monica, CA Apr 2019-Present

Director, Software Engineering

- Disnev+
- Leads the Disney+ Presentation Team, responsible for the end-to-end development and delivery of consumer-facing features across mobile clients, living room devices and web-based platforms
- Manages backend services team that builds and maintains client facing experience APIs requiring 100% uptime with low latency and high throughput for over 100 million subscribers
- Overall engineering lead for launch of ESPN on Disney+ domestically, adding availability for over 4k pieces of original sports content and ~30k yearly live sports events to Disney+ bundle subscribers in an integrated app experience
- Launched Hulu on Disney+ leading engineering effort to build new client-facing API tier to support new general entertainment experience and 3x expansion of available SVOD catalog
- National Geographic
- Led full stack engineering team for National Geographic's primary consumer facing mobile applications and website, bringing availability of online articles and over 100 years of print magazine content in a modern digital experience
- Co-led consecutive large scale consolidation and re-platforming efforts to migrate ABC News,
 Marvel and National Geographic's sites and mobile apps to a new modernized in house platform with multi-million dollar savings implications for the company

Manager/Senior Manager, Software Engineering

Jan 2014-Apr 2019

- Technical lead of the web platform engineering team, responsible for the architecture and development of over 50 systems and tools, including content, data and asset management systems that support numerous web and mobile app experiences across the Disney portfolio
- Led large-scale initiative as the primary technical and project leader to move Disney Interactive's main web platform to Google Cloud, featuring more than 30 major systems that support over 800 guest-facing sites, including Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com, resulting in multi-million dollar cost savings in system operations year over year
- Led product and engineering for backend content management and data platform, which powers Disney's flagship responsive websites disney.com and starwars.com
- Primary technical partner to product solutions team, providing technical guidance and custombuilt solutions to meet the needs of multiple stakeholders and global content production teams
- Managed revision of recommendation engine for Disney video portal that suggests related content through machine learning using Hadoop

Disney (cont.) Glendale, CA

Senior/Staff Software Engineer

May 2011-Dec 2013

- Architected and built an entirely new search platform for the major relaunch of disney.com using open-source software and frameworks like Apache Solr and Spring
- Optimized primary search algorithm leading to an increase in direct affiliate revenue from search on disney.com over 500% year over year
- Migrated several legacy disney.com sites and portals onto search platform, including Disney Channel, Disney XD and Walt Disney Company corporate sites
- Led front end and search engineering teams responsible for newly relaunched disney.com along with several internationalized companion sites in Latin America and Europe

CityGrid Media/Citysearch

West Hollywood, CA

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2008-Apr 2011

- Led team of engineers in deployment of new search functionality during major site redesign with algorithm improvements leading to increases in conversions and revenue of over \$500k per year
- Architected and scaled multiple clusters of Apache Solr-based indexes containing more than
 18 million unique business listings performing advanced geo-spatial local searches
- Principal engineer on cross-functional scrum team responsible for building RESTful web applications for submission of user generated content including images, reviews and tweets

Warner Bros. Advanced Digital Services

Burbank, CA

Associate Application Engineer

May 2006-Apr 2008

Led development of online video distribution applications for both client and server utilizing
 Java technologies and Windows DRM to generate cost savings of over \$1 million for studio

Education

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

B.S. Computer Engineering and Computer Science

December 2005

- · Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- USC Presidential Scholar
- USC SCion Scholar

\sim		-
2	ΚI	IIS

Executive Leadership Cross-functional Delivery Amazon Web Services
Technical Strategy Agile Methodologies Google Cloud Platform
Large Scale Program Mgmt Scrum / Kanban Google App Engine

JavaRuby on RailsDockerRubySinatraKubernetes

HTML5 MongoDB Web Services/APIs

JavaScript SQL REST CSS Apache Solr

Lucene Mac OS X

Spring Framework Unix/Linux
Hibernate Continuous Integration